Rakshain!
ラクシャイーン！
Lady Touka!
トウカ殿！
You're safe?
無事であったか
Lord Orikakan, I'm afraid I lacked
the necessary skill.
オリカカン殿
某が未熟なばかりに…
No, it was not your fault.
いや
トウカ殿のせいではない
They are cowards!
奴らが卑劣なのだ
I swear in the name of the Evankulga...
エヴェンクルガの名にかけて…
They will not escape me next time.
次は逃がさぬ
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
Hey, did you hear?
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空 果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に 充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼(はね)を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ 行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから 一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
おいおい 聞いたかい？
Yeah, that there were Evankulga
among the enemy, right?
ああ 敵の中に
エヴェンクルガ族がいたって話だろう？
A Bloody Battle
Sounds like it's true.
どうやらそれ 本当の事らしいぜ
Why would the Evankulga ally themselves
with those barbarians?
なんでエヴェンクルガが
パン族の味方をするんだよ
Hey, what's an "Evankulga"?
ねえ
エヴェンクルガってなあに？
おお エヴェンクルガってえのはな
The Evankulga are proud warriors
世の善人を助け悪を討つ 誇り高き
who help the good people of the world
in the fight against evil, and...
ハクオロ様が悪い人なの？
Is Hakuoro-sama an evil person?
After that, Orikakan's cavalry split up
to throw off our pursuit.
その後
オリカカンのラクシャライは
我々に足取りを掴ませぬよう分散
They disappeared into the night.
闇夜に紛れて姿を消しました
I have singled out several possible
points where they might regroup
現在 いくつか合流地点の目星を付け
調査に向かわせています
and sent men to scout them out.
What of the civilians?
民の様子はどうだ？
構わん 言ってくれ
It is all right. Tell me.
They are all uneasy.
皆 動揺しております
I see, of course...
そうか… そうだな
ご苦労 休んでくれ
You've done well. Go and rest now.
Yes, Sire.
Please get some rest yourself, Sire.
聖上もお休みになってください
It's a leader's job to be prepared for anything.
万事に備えるのも 指導者の務めです
I guess you're right.
そうだな
ううーん いい香りですわぁ
Oh, now that smells nice!
Karula-san! You can't have this.
カルラさん
ダメですよ
これはハクオロさんの…
It's for Hakuoro-san.
Actually...
Why don't you join him, Karula-san?
良かったら カラルさんも
ご一緒にいかがです？
まあ！ よろしいんですの？
Oh! Would that be all right?
フッ ウフフ
I appreciate the offer,
but I shouldn't butt in.
せっかくですけど
邪魔しては悪いですわね
Huh? Huh!?
This is a good opportunity.
Go have him indulge you.
いい機会ですから 甘えてらっしゃいな
That's not...
そんな…
あ この場合逆ですわねえ
Well, I guess it'd be the
opposite in this case.
When a man is suffering, it is the
woman's duty to indulge him.
その方が辛い時には
甘えさせてあげるのも女の務めですし
Well, I must be going.
そ… それじゃあ私 行きますから
そのぐらいにして
もうお休みになった方が…
Don't you think you should call it
a night and go to bed?
いや
No, let me drink a little more.
もう少し飲ませてくれ
As a healer, I can't allow you to
keep this up day after day!
毎日こんな事を続けて
薬師として黙っている訳にはいきません！
Are you worried about my health?
私の体が心配か？
Of course!
当たり前です！
You scold me about the same thing every day.
毎日エルルゥは 同じ事で叱ってくれる
That's because you keep on drinking
without getting any rest.
ハクオロさんがお休みにならず
そんなに飲み続けるからです
If I had a mother, would she
say the same thing?
母親がいたら…
同じ事を言うのだろうか？
A mother?
お母さん…
父親ならば…
怒鳴りつけてくれるのだろうか？
Would a father yell at me?
Hakuoro-san...
ハクオロさん…
Not knowing my father or mother
父も母も知らぬ私が
and being without memories as I am,
自らの記憶を持たない私が
I see you as something like a mother.
君を母のようだと言う
Hakuoro-san...
ハクオロさん
自分が何者か分からぬ不安に怯えるなんて
Isn't it ridiculous how overcome by fear I am
due to the uncertainty of my own identity?
滑稽じゃないか
Who in the world am I?
私は… 何者なのだ！
It doesn't matter who you are.
ハクオロさんが誰だなんて
どうだっていいんです
Doesn't matter?
どうだっていい？
To me, you are who you are, Hakuoro-san.
私にとってハクオロさんは
ハクオロさんなんです
I... I...
私は 私は…
あっあー！
あ あ… ハクオロさん
Hakuoro-san...
Aren't you afraid of me?
君は私が怖くはないのか？
I'm sorry. Please leave me.
すまない 下がってくれ
I will never be afraid of you.
私がハクオロさんを怖いと思うなんて
絶対ありません
It's all right.
大丈夫です　大丈夫…
It's all right...
I...
私は…
Kurou, have you seen my brother?
クロウ 兄者 見なかったか？
No, isn't he in his room?
いや
部屋にはいないのか？
こんな大変な時に どこに行ったんだ？
Where could he have gone at
such a difficult time?
His Highness must have his reasons.
聖上にも お考えがあるのでしょう
Maybe so, but there's no telling when the
Kuccha Kecchans will attack again!
そうなんだろうが
いつクッチャケッチャの連中が攻めて来るか
知れないんだぞ
Eruruu-sama!
-エルルゥ様ー
-ん？
What's wrong?
どうなさいました？
We're looking for Eruruu-sama to
get some healing ointment.
傷薬をいただきたくて
エルルゥ様を捜しているんですけど
If you need healing ointment,
I shall prepare some for you.
傷薬でしたら わたくしがご用意します
-グフ　ウッフ
-えへ へっ
Yippee!
キャッホー！
Now, listen! You mustn't go too far!
こーらー！
あんまり遠くへ行っちゃダメよー！
Hakuoro-san, thank you for coming with us.
ハクオロさん 今日は付き合ってもらって
ありがとうございます
But I guess I kind of forced you to.
というより 私が無理やり
引っ張ってきちゃったんですね
Eruruu, I...
エルルゥ
私は…
Yes, that's right.
Everyone must be worried.
そうですよね
みんな心配してますよね
You are their king after all.
ハクオロさんは
みんなのハクオロ王なんですよね
I think you...
私は君に…
But I think a change of pace
is important sometimes.
でもたまには息抜きも必要だと思うんです
Why do you do it?
君は…
どうして…
Huh?
Why do you give me your support?
私を支えてくれるんだ？
I'm always so harsh towards you.
私は君に辛く当たってばかりいる
それは私が…
It's because I...
Because...
それは…
はあっ 覚えてますか？
Do you remember?
You called us your family that time.
ハクオロさんは 私達のこと
家族って言ってくれましたよね？
Isn't that reason enough?
それが理由じゃあ ダメですか？
ああ… そんな深い意味はありません
There's no deeper reason or anything!
I just... Well, I mean I, well...
あの ただ その えーと
あの…
Father!
お父さーん
-ウォーファッハー
-フハッ エヘーッ ヘ ヘッ
-ガルウ フオー グオー アオーウ
-んー フッフッ ヘッヘッ
This is fun, isn't it, Father?
楽しいね お父さん
Isn't it?
楽しいね キャハッ フフッ フフッ フフッ
あは…
Yes, it is.
ああ そうだな
-エヘッ お父さん！
-おっと
Father!
-んっ は…
-フッフッ ヘヘッ エヘッ
-ガルーオーッ
-だあっ！ とっ！
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハッ
アッハッハッハッハッハッ ハハッ
んー こら やめないか ムックル
Here now, stop that, Mukkuru!
キャハッ エヘヘッエヘヘッ
Oh...
あれ？
The enemy! The enemy!
敵襲ーっ！
敵襲ぅーっ！
All right! Here they come!
よっしゃあー！
来やがったか
Brother!
兄者
Forward!
出陣！
King Hakuoro, is this army large enough?
ハクオロ王
こんな人数で大丈夫なのですか？
Might this be reckless?
無謀なのでは？
The enemy moves quickly.
敵の足は速い
疲弊した兵を連れていけば
こちらの被害が増えるばかりだ
Facing them with exhausted soldiers
will only increase our losses.
That may be so, but still...
それはそうなのでしょうが…
ま 心配すんなって事だ
Do not worry.
Mukkuru, you will protect the gate.
ムックル！
門を守るのはお前だ
ウゴゥ
Do not worry, I am myself.
大丈夫
私は私だ
ガルゥ
This is an important battle.
Don't let your guard down.
大事な戦だ
気を抜くんじゃないぞ！
あなたこそ
力んでばかりでは よくありませんわよ
The same to you. Simply putting on a tough
front isn't going to work either.
Oh, my...
あーら
ワオーオ アオーオー
It's not time to eat yet.
ご飯まだ
グウ
This is an unfortunate turn of events.
残念な事になりました
I guess it means they undoubtedly were
savages from the borderlands.
やはり 辺境の蛮族には
違いなかったという事でしょうか？
King Hakuoro is an earnest man.
ハクオロ王は賢明な方です
By standing at the forefront, he is attempting
to give guidance to his people.
あの方は 自ら先頭に立つ事で
皆の導き手にならんとしています
カミュ？
Camus!
ぬうっ！
Princess!
姫様っ！
あー お姉様
Big sister...
I, well, kinda thought maybe I'd help him.
これは おじ様の助っ人に！
なんて…
That won't do at all!
ぬあー なりませんぞ！
An envoy of the Onkamiyamukai must never
go into battle of her own free will!
オンカミヤムカイの使者が
進んで戦場に立つことなぞっ！
もおーぉ
Big sister!
おねーさまーぁ
Camus, Munto is exactly right.
カミュ… ムントの言う通りですよ
ほーら
You see?
Big sister, he'll be all right, won't he?
お姉様 おじ様大丈夫だよね？
It will surely be a fierce battle.
厳しい戦でしょうが…
But the time has come for this country
to overcome its ordeal.
今この国は 試練を乗り越えなくては
ならない時なのです
Mister...
おじ様…
May Witsalnemitea protect them.
ウィツァルネミテアのご加護を
Not a single one of the soldiers
I sent after them has returned.
追跡に出した兵は
１人も戻って来ませんでした
They've most likely perished.
恐らく…
Damn them!
くそおっ！ あいつらぁ
The enemy is dauntless.
敵は勇猛だ
甘く見ていては押し潰されるぞ！
If we take them lightly, we will be crushed.
いいねえー
Great, I like the sound of this.
こういうのは嫌いじゃねえ
Brother!
兄者！
Sire!
聖上！
Let's settle this!
決着をつけるっ！
やああーっ！
ぬうーっ！
Just as we want. Now tear them apart!
望むところ！
食い破れーっ！
No tricks this time, I'm impressed.
小細工無しとは見直した！
ラクシャイーン！
Rakshain!
Where is Rakshain!?
ラクシャインはどこだーっ？
のおっ！
Make way, if you value your life!
命が惜しくば 道を空けよっ！
ええーいっ！
やあっ！
An Evankulga...
エヴェンクルガたぁ
A good enough match for me!
相手にとって…
不足はねえっ！
ふんっ！
-んんっ！
-てあっ！
どぉうらっ
やあっ
Rakshain!
ラクシャイーンッ！
ラクシャインッ！
Rakshain!
Stop! You're not getting away!
待てーっ！ 逃げるかーっ！
Lord Orikakan!
オリカカン殿！
-ぬうーっ！
-うっ
You mustn't pursue him on
your own, Lord Orikakan!
お一人で追われては なりません！
オリカカン殿っ！
いやっ！
Kurou, don't let her go after them!
クロウ 追わせるな！
あーら
My, my...
I'm not letting you pass.
こちらへは行かせませんわよ
It appears that this is what we
must do to stop you.
こうでもしないと…
あなたを足止めできないようですので
フッフフフフフ
Damn cowards...
卑怯者どもが
What can I say?
何とも…
-ふっ！ どぅあっ！
-んえぃっ！
えいっ！
ぬうっ！
Don't expect a painless death!
楽に死ねると 思うなっ！
-どぅあっ！
-いっ！
どぅあっ！
おおわっ！
Damn you! Stop!
貴様あ！
止まれーっ！
あはっ
ふんっ
待ーてーっ！
Hold it!
I guess we'll fight another day.
勝負はお預けですわね
ひうっ！
ハッハッハッハー！
I've got you now, Rakshain!
追い詰めたぞラクシャイン！
Are you now a stranger to the
feeling of fear as well?
怯える心も とうに無くしたか！
It was my plan to draw you out here.
ここへ誘い出したのは 策の内だ！
Do you intend to beg for your life?
I refuse to listen!
命乞いのつもりか
聞く耳持たぬ！
I did not think that I would get a chance
to talk to you unless I did this.
こうでもしないと
貴様と話ができないと思ったのでな
にいいっ…
Don't take me for a fool!
舐ぁめるなーっ！
I will ask you again...
今一度 問う
Do you really know about my past?
本当に私の過去を知っているのか？
Enough of this!
くどいっ！
ふいっ！
でえっ！
ぬおおっ！
うう ラクシャインン…
Rakshain...
That is as far as you go.
ここまでだ
い ヌッハハハハハハ
How does it feel right now?
どうだ今の気分は？
You killed your wife, killed your children,
おのが妻を殺し 子を殺し
余から全てを奪い晒し者にする
stole everything from me and
exposed me to such ridicule.
It must be the greatest feeling to you.
さぞ最高の気分だろうな
So what's wrong? Go on and kill me!
さぁ どうした？
殺すがいいっ！
Kill me with your own hands,
the way you killed my sister!
我が妹を殺したように
貴様の手で殺すがいい
Rakshain!
ラクシャイン！
はうっ
You're wrong!
違う！
Are you still denying it?
この期に及んで まだとぼけるのか？
I am Hakuoro!
私はハクオロだ！
I am not Rakshain!
ラクシャインなどではないっ！
Nonsense.
戯れ言を…
Even if you truly have lost your memories,
it doesn't erase your crimes!
例え記憶を無くそうとも
貴様の罪は消えぬ！
Crimes?
罪？
そうだ
That's right.
Those blood-stained hands are
the unshakeable proof!
その血塗られた手が 何よりの証拠だ！
はあはっ…
Crimes?
罪？
ああはっ
おっおおーっ こっ…
Crime...
罪？
Something as small as this?
この程度の事がかっ？
Who... Who in the world are you!?
誰だ？
貴様一体 何者だ？
I am...
-私は…
-え… へっ へっひ…
よっ 寄るなっ
D... Don't come near me!
Wait!
待て… 何を言っている？
What are you saying?
What are you seeing in me?
お前は私の何を見ているのだ？
はっ… ははーっ　あがっ！
なあっ！
カーッカッカッカッカッカッカハハッ
-そいつの役目はそこまでよ
-くうっ！
He has outlived his usefulness!
It was all for you!
全ては貴様のため！
I only used him to agitate you.
貴様を煽るために その男を利用したまで
カーッカッカッカッカッカッカッカッ
Why did you do this!?
何故こんな真似をするのだっ？
There you go! That anger...
そうだ その怒り！
I want to see the beast that
sleeps within you.
余は貴様の中に眠る獣を見たいのだ
カーッカッカッカッカッカッ
ハッハッハッハッ
Rage on! Hate! Loathe!
怒れ！ 恨め！ 憎しめ！
Those emotions are the source
of people's strength!
それこそが人の力の源
They are the source of my own delight!
余を楽しませる源よ！
カーッカッカッカッカッ
カッカッカッカッカ
What a despicable thing.
何という事だ
Lord Orikakan, I have done
irrevocable damage!
オリカカン殿
某は…
取り返しのつかない事を
カーッカッカッ
Sorcery can be a most
interesting deception, no?
幻術とは 面白い謀りよのう
Hakuoro-sama!
Hakuoro-san!
ハクオロさん！
I'm back.
ただいま
Welcome home.
お帰りなさい
カーッカッカッカッカッカッ
カッカッカッカ
カッカッカッカッカッカ
カーッカッカッカッカッカッカッ
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
孤独の中求む
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼 祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼 弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす 輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし 詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
The Ravages of War